

WIM BOSMANS

OPERATIONS MANAGER

Operational Excellence | Change Management | Organizational Development

Dedicated, technical-savvy & goal-driven Operations Manager with over 12 years experience in project management and strategic business leadership.

Offers expertise spanning operational excellence and change management, able to inspire and cultivate a productive working relationship with employees.

Analytical thinker able to evaluate complex situations and implement improvements that have dramatically impacted OPEX and lowered the prospect of on-the-job incidents.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Critical thinking | Open minded | Pro-active | Problem solving | Decision making | Analytical wizard
- Maritime operations | Asset management | Supply Chain Management | Planning & Implementation | Risk management | Scheduling | Budgeting
- Strategic planning | Organizational Development | Project Chartering | Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & KPI's |

 Continuous Improvement | Scorecards & Score
- Communication & Presentation | Lean six sigma | Toyota Business Practice | Hierarchy of controls | Ishikawa | Safety by Design
- Dutch (native) | English (fluent) | French (basic)

EXPERIENCE

DEME - Dredging International 09/2011-PRESENT

Head of Project Launch Department - Zwijndrecht, Belgium 06/2020-PRESENT

Responsible for departments Dredge pipes & Cutter heads, Mobdemob, Lay-down HQ & Business Partner Procurement.

Accountable for the successful mobilization of operational critical mission equipment and to streamline procurement on projects.

- Coordinated the blue print design of the new Project Launch Department
- Initiated the DEME Safe Logistics project and prevented HiPo incidents from happening in 2020
- · Transformed communication methods to re-align & focus workforce's efforts to ensure operational logistic excellence.
- Designed & implemented a cost economical router to reduce transit costs by 3-5% (€1.5M/annum)
- Created & implemented the mobilization proposal to reduce TCO cost by 3-5% ($\!\in\!$ 500k/annum)

Logistics Manager - Zwijndrecht, Belgium 02/2017-05/2020

Responsible for departments Dredge pipes & Cutter heads, mobdemob, Charter Desk, Transport, Warehouse & Shipment and Lay-down HQ.

Accountable for mobilization of operational critical mission equipment & distribution of procured goods to projects.

- Set up & launched strategic programs per supply chain and identified key improvement projects
- Organized active wear follow up on project Tema to reduce wear by 10% (\leqslant 150k)
- • Reduced TCO by 4% (€250k/annum) by implementing an improved inventory policy

$Coordinator\ Mission\ Equipment\ -\ Zwijndrecht,\ Belgium\ 09/2014-01/2017$

 $Responsible \ for \ worldwide \ operational \ planning \ \& \ life \ cycle \ management \ of \ mission \ critical \ equipment.$

- Initiated turn-key solutions to deliver mission equipment first time right
- Implemented mobilization dashboards as single source of truth to significantly improve & centralize communication across departments & projects

$Superintendent (SI)/Works\ Manager (WM) - Perth, AU\ /\ Bremen, DE\ /\ Onne, NI\ 12/2012-08/2014$

Manage and successfully coordinate operations of production units on projects according to plan.

- Onne Port Expansion: Launched CTOW business unit to enter towing operations market
- Bremen Kohlenhafen: WM for backhoe dredge (BHD) Peter The Great
- Wheatstone project: SI for dry-dock operations of CSD Ambiorix (Singapore)

Production Engineer / Superintendent - Panama City, Panama 06/2012-11/2012

Responsible to explore & evaluate alternative dredge methods to optimize production.

- Developed & implemented a pressure release valve into dredge line to save 35% on delays (€300k)
- Reduced operational delays up to 30% by standardizing & communicating SOP's with crew (€1.7M)

Project Engineer - Colonia Del Sacramento, Uruguay 09/2011-05/2012

Responsible to design and execute the test protocol for a high pressure water jetting prototype.

- Coordinated the installation of the prototype and successfully launched system into operation
- Gathered all relevant information and compiled it into an operator's manual

TOYOTA Motor Europe (TME) - Zaventem, Belgium 08/2008-08/2011

Chassis Project Engineer

Responsible for the design & development of suspensions parts.

- Engineered a solution to a road noise design issue to resolve a customer complaint problem
 - Reduced costs on suspension parts (€100k/annum) by changing identifiers & materials used

EDUCATION

Catholic University of Leuven (KUL) - Leuven, Belgium

Master of Science in Mechanical - Electro technical Engineering, 06/2008